<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Johnny O&#39;Rourke</title>
    <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Johnny O&#39;Rourke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 09:32:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://TacticalPants.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock Detection Application</title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/big-rock-doctor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 09:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/big-rock-doctor/</guid>
      <description>This application allows a user to submit a photo of a rock or any other object and it will determine if the photo was of a rock or not.
This project was conceived after reading the book &amp;ldquo;The Geology of New York City and environs&amp;rdquo;. The book is a riveting tour of basic geologic theory and the geologic history of New York, from 2 billion years ago until 1970, when the book was written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorythm Trade Bot</title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/second-post/</guid>
      <description>This tool requests live market data from the Alpha Vantage API which can be viewed and processed and trades can be made using a trade API, this application uses Alpaca.
The tool is run from a desktop GUI interface. The project collects data from the Alpha Vantage api, initializes and stores the data in a Mongodb, and plots the data in graph form in the GUI. The tool in its current form imports several cryptocurrencies but can be modified to view or trade anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Browser</title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple HTML parsing browser written in Python. This project was a learning exercise and not for production. I sought to learn the basic mechanisms of how to build a web browser that connects with a host, retrieves information, and presents it. There is a lot more I could do with this product to make it more robust but I&amp;rsquo;m not looking to build a new Chrome, nor would that be a healthy learning exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Port Neches Plant Explosion</title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/port-neches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/port-neches/</guid>
      <description>Following an oil plant explosion in Port Neches, Texas we were hired to determine the structural safety of the plant for rescue teams and fire fighters to enter. Following the stabilization of the plant we investigated the soundness of all the houses and buildings in the surrounding area. The blast radius was several miles in diameter so the project encompassed investigating thousands of structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ports America Newark </title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/ports-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/ports-america/</guid>
      <description>I performed a structural, site and facility assessment, and in conjunction with another firm determined what upgrades were necessary for the site to maintain operation with a potentially rising sea level and more frequent damaging hurricanes in the New York Harbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drone Investigation Jersey City </title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/drone-nj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/drone-nj/</guid>
      <description>I founded and developed the drone building inspection program at CCA. The program acquired projects that required the inspection of the façade and roof condition of buildings in select projects in: New York, NY, Jersey City, NJ, Boston, MA, Worcester, MA, and Houston, TX. This photo was taken at an investigation of the Dixon MIlls Condominiums. The building used to operate as the Dixon Mills-Ticonderoga pencil manufacturing plant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frenchmans Reef St. Thomas </title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/frenchmans-reef/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/frenchmans-reef/</guid>
      <description>Following Hurricanes Maria and Irene our comapny was tasked with establishing a team of specialized construction experts and assessing the damage to a large multi-building resort and campus, stabilizing the campus to operational and safe condition, redesigning, and overseeing the repair and construction the structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Tux Ketchum </title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/winter-tux-ketchum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/winter-tux-ketchum/</guid>
      <description>This was a passion project for our engineering firm. We designed several log cabins during my time with Maxwell SDS but this one was unique in that it was roughly 15 miles away from the nearest road. There were no electrical services or running water at the plot. Although the county that the cabin was built in we designed it to the ASCE 7-16 witch includes a large snowload due the elevation and location in the mountains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thudner Springs Residences Ketchum </title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/thunder-springs-idaho/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/thunder-springs-idaho/</guid>
      <description>I served as the lead structural engineer for seven, high-end, four-story condominium buildings in Sun Valley, Idaho. This project required the design of all framing systems and custom components and included concrete retaining foundations, steel column and beam structures, and wood timber framing. The substantial snow load and earthquake load incurred in this region of Idaho proved to make designing a structure with many window surfaces a unique challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irene Street Ketchum</title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/irene-street-idaho/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/structure/irene-street-idaho/</guid>
      <description>This is a high end residential building in Ketchum, Idaho that I feel is indicative of the typical design and construction type that I worked on while living in Idaho.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>