<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Softwares on Johnny O&#39;Rourke</title>
    <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Softwares on Johnny O&#39;Rourke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 09:32:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock Detection Application</title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/big-rock-doctor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 09:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/big-rock-doctor/</guid>
      <description>This application allows a user to submit a photo of a rock or any other object and it will determine if the photo was of a rock or not.
This project was conceived after reading the book &amp;ldquo;The Geology of New York City and environs&amp;rdquo;. The book is a riveting tour of basic geologic theory and the geologic history of New York, from 2 billion years ago until 1970, when the book was written.</description>
    </item>
	
    <item>
      <title>Data Server</title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/data_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/data_server/</guid>
      <description>This project creates a data server on a Raspberry Pi.  And Flask API sends information from an application to the data sever where a neural network procesesses the information and retern the determination to the applicaion.  This server was the precurser to Rock Doctor, that is on my Github, that utilizes Google Firebase for ML processing.</description>
    </item>
	  
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic Trade Bot</title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/second-post/</guid>
      <description>This tool requests live market data from the Alpha Vantage API which can be viewed and processed and trades can be made using a trade API, this application uses Alpaca.
The tool is run from a desktop GUI interface. The project collects data from the Alpha Vantage api, initializes and stores the data in a Mongodb, and plots the data in graph form in the GUI. The tool in its current form imports several cryptocurrencies but can be modified to view or trade anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Browser</title>
      <link>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://TacticalPants.github.io/software/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple HTML parsing browser written in Python. This project was a learning exercise and not for production. I sought to learn the basic mechanisms of how to build a web browser that connects with a host, retrieves information, and presents it. There is a lot more I could do with this product to make it more robust but I&amp;rsquo;m not looking to build a new Chrome, nor would that be a healthy learning exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
